#### Contact

andrewcraigrn@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/andrewcraigrn (LinkedIn)

AndrewCraigRN.com (Personal)

## Top Skills

Nursing
Social Media Marketing
Online Community Management

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### **Publications**

7 undeniable signs you were meant to be a travel nurse

7 things I wish I knew before I started travel nursing

How much do travel nurses make?

Travel Nurse Housing: The Definitive Guide 2017

How to adapt to the short travel nurse orientation

# Andrew Craig, BSN, RN

Making a positive difference one patient at a time Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area

## Summary

Andrew Craig, RN is a passionate registered nurse with a BSN and currently working on his MSN of Nursing Education. Mr. Craig has 5 years of diverse nursing experience in acute care, skilled nursing, community outreach, and education. Mr. Craig is a professional who is adaptable and specializes in evidenced based, safe, and patient centered care. Being highly punctual, Mr. Craig strives for integrity and excellence with each patient interaction. Mr. Craig is a compassionate gentleman who treats each patient with respect and dignity.

Andrew Craig, RN has always been interested in make a difference and helping people. Mr. Craig knew from his emergency department volunteering experiences in college that nursing was the career for him. He enjoyed the fast pace and the challenge nursing offered. But, also, the positive difference nurses make in a person's life. He quit his job in construction and began classes at a local community college. He hasn't looked back since.

Andrew Craig, RN has had the privilege to work in several rewarding clinical positions. Mr. Craig started his hospital career at the University of Iowa Hospital. From there, he joined a travel nursing company for new clinical experiences and a little adventure. He's worked in Minnesota, Oregon, and plans to work in California and Washington. Mr. Craig currently travels the country (and the world) with his wife Sarah who is also a registered nurse. The two often work the same unit together.

Mr. Craig's nursing specialties are in:

- Nursing Process and Care Plan Development
- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration
- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving
- Communication and Patient Education
- Clinical Leadership and Professionalism

## Computer Skills and Technology

I am currently seeking new nursing career opportunities and can be reached at AndrewCraigRN@yahoo.com, AndrewCraigRN.com, or (319) 212-0337. I'm available anytime to call. I'm working day shift now.

## Experience

**UW Health** 

1 year 8 months

Primacy Care Float Nursing Supervisor August 2019 - Present (11 months)

Madison, Wisconsin Area

Supervise and coordinate staffing of a 100 member float team; including, registered nurses, medical assistants, and patient service representatives.

Provide float services to a 90 primary and specialty care clinics through Dane Country, Wisconsin.

Supervise a team of 26 nurses on a remote, central triage float team.

Staff Registered Nurse (Ambulatory Specialty Float Pool) November 2018 - August 2019 (10 months)

Madison, Wisconsin Area

Provided float nurse triage services to specialty clinics; including, Endocrine, Diabetes, Pulmonary, and Cardiology.

Covenant Medical Center
Travel Nurse
January 2018 - October 2018 (10 months)
Waterloo, Iowa Area

University of Wisconsin Hospital and Clinics Travel Registered Nurse (Trauma-Surgical Intermediate Care Unit) February 2017 - December 2017 (11 months) Madison, Wisconsin Area

A level 1 trauma center and teaching hospital with 505 beds. Recognized as the #1 hospital in Wisconsin by U.S. News and World Report and is a Magnet

Hospital for Nursing Excellence. In 2015, UW Hospital had 30,794 admissions, 32,773 surgeries, and 55,660 ED visits.

Travel Nurse (Trauma-Surgical Intermediate Care Unit)

Provide top-notch, evidenced based nursing care to complicated trauma,
orthopedic, and surgical patients while implementing the nursing process and
medical plan of care.

- Nursing Process and Care Plan Development: Gather nursing assessment data to plan individualized nursing care plans to promote healing, prevent infections, and promote appropriate fluid and electrolyte balance.
- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration: Collaborate with the orthopedic, trauma, and surgical teams to plan nursing and medical care for complex patients; such as, motor vehicle accidents, multiple fractures, head traumas, and respiratory distress.
- Computer Skills and Technology: Utilizing Epic Charting systems to document pertinent clinical and patient data. Analyze data via Epic systems; such as, laboratory results, vital signs, history and physicals, and visual diagnostics to prevent complications and promote good patient outcomes.

#### **Medical Solutions**

Travel Registered Nurse (Step Down Unit-Progressive Care) August 2016 - January 2017 (6 months)

Klamath Falls, Oregon

Sky Lakes Medical Center is a regional, level 3 trauma center with 176 beds and is affiliated with University of Oregon Medical School. In 2010, Sky Lakes had 6,112 admissions, 6,741 surgical procedures, and 23,248 emergency room visits.

Provided excellent nursing care by gathering data, assessments, and implementing the nursing process while collaboratively working with medical staff to provide prescribed medications and treatments.

 Nursing Process and Care Plan Development: Collected assessment data to develop patient specific nursing care plans with diseases; such as, sepsis, acute myocardial infarction, or alcohol and illicit drug withdrawal.

- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration: Collaborated with the multidisciplinary team to coordinate discharge plans for challenging patient populations with drug abuse, alcohol abuse, or complex comorbidities.
- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving: Demonstrated safety awareness
  by identifying possible causes of sepsis or respiratory distress by analyzing
  clinical data, laboratory data, and physical assessment findings to plan nursing
  care, identify covert complications, and help coordinate medical treatment.

University of Minnesota Medical Center (Medical Solutions) Travel Registered Nurse (Step Down Unit-Progressive Care) January 2016 - July 2016 (7 months)

Minneapolis, Minnesota

A level 2 trauma center and teaching hospital with 839 beds, and had the world's first open heart transplant surgeries. In one year, Fairview had 34, 256 admissions, 23, 843 surgeries, and 57, 299 ED visits.

Collaboratively restored patient health by implementing nursing care plans, identifying complications, giving medications, and implementing medical orders on a fast paced and busy step-down unit.

- Nursing Process and Care Plan Development: Frequently implemented nursing care for complicated liver failure patients focusing on the ABCs, hemodynamics, blood loss, multi-system dysfunction, fluid and electrolytes, antibiotics, malnutrition, urine output, IV medication administration, and lab data.
- Communication and Patient Education: Efficiently and accurately documented nursing care on the EPIC EMR system while effectively using quality verbal communication for bedside patient report hand-off, SBAR report to physicians, and patient specific education.
- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving: Implemented cardiac drips; such as, Nitroglycerin, Heparin, Amiodarone, Diltiazem, or Esmolol during emergent or ACLS situations; such as, acute MI, SVT, a-fib with RVR, and hypertensive emergencies.

University of Iowa Hospital and Clinics Staff Nurse (Respiratory Specialty and Comprehensive Care Unit) September 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 4 months) Iowa City, Iowa

A level 1 trauma center and teaching hospital with 732 beds and the Magnet Award for Nursing Excellence. In 2015, Iowa had 33,000 acute admissions, 935,000 clinic visits, and 57,000 Emergency visits.

Applied evidenced based practice to the assessment, diagnosis, treatment, and evaluation of patient responses to respiratory, medical, and palliative care populations.

- Nursing Process and Care Plan Development: Provided focused assessments for specialized pulmonary patients with severe COPD, respiratory failure, cystic fibrosis, mechanical ventilation, or lung transplants often with severe respiratory distress to develop, update, implement, and evaluate nursing care plans.
- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration: Collaborated with respiratory, medical, palliative, and on-call resident teams to plan nursing care while appropriately delegating nursing care to CNAs and ancillary staff.
- Communication and Patient Education: To enhance nurse-patient relationship and improve patient outcomes, frequently spent extra time teaching and communicating unique discharge education for patients with new tracheostomies, lung transplants, new Type 2 diabetics, or complicated medication regimes.

Briarwood Healthcare Center Night Charge Registered Nurse January 2014 - September 2014 (9 months) Iowa City, Iowa

A skilled nursing facility with 64 beds focused on providing quality healthcare, compassion, and integrity. Holding a Medicare rating of 93/100, Briarwood is one of the highest ranked nursing facilities in Iowa.

Managed and supervised nightly activities of the facility; including, medication administration, prescribed treatments, and activities of daily living.

 Nursing Process and Care Plan Development: Planned and implemented nursing care plans for skilled nursing residents with conditions; such as, wound care, pneumonia, hip fracture, or infections. Parkview of Wellman Nursing Home Night Charge Registered Nurse April 2013 - January 2014 (10 months)

Wellman, Iowa

A skilled nursing facility with 62 beds focused on comprehensive care services; including, respite care, assisted living, long-term care, hospice, and a secure memory unit.

Managed and supervised nightly activities of the facility; including, medication administration, prescribed treatments, and activities of daily living.

 Communication and Patient Education: Collaborated and appropriately delegated nursing care to CNAs and ancillary to care for individual resident needs. Provided hospice and end of life education to patients and families.

Black Hawk College 3 years

Research Assistant 2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Moline. Illinois

Founded in a small high school in 1946 to accommodate World II veterans, the college now serves 2,200 square miles and nine counties. Admits 7,000 students each year and is accredited by the Higher Learning Commission (HLC), Academic Quality Improvement Program Pathway (AQIP), and Commission for Education in Nursing (ACEN).

- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration: Assisted senior researchers and Biology professors conduct complex Phylogenetic research and experimentation on the snake species Nerodia Erythrogaster.
- Computer Skills and Technology: Implemented standardized protocols and procedures to operate scientific equipment; such as, incubators, homogenizers, spectrophotometers, centrifuges, and PCR workstations.

Biochemistry Lab Technician 2009 - 2011 (2 years) Moline, Illinois

Founded in a small high school in 1946 to accommodate World II veterans, the college now serves 2,200 square miles and nine counties. Admits 7,000

students each year and is accredited by the Higher Learning Commission (HLC), Academic Quality Improvement Program Pathway (AQIP), and Commission for Education in Nursing (ACEN).

- Team work and Multidisciplinary Collaboration: Assisted Biology and Chemistry professors prepare chemical solutions for laboratory experimentation.
- Computer Skills and Technology: Prepared biological media and cultures from specific scientific procedures. Arranged laboratory equipment and instrumentation required for Biology, Chemistry, Microbiology, and Physiology courses.

## Education

Western Governors University

Master's degree (Currently Incomplete), Nursing Education · (2017 - June 2018)

Western Governors University

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing · (2013 - 2015)

Black Hawk College

Associate of Science (AS), Registered Nursing · (2009 - 2012)